<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-14T15:45:15-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Curated Insights</title><subtitle>A Blog Theme by Start Bootstrap</subtitle><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><entry><title type="html">Brazil’s Real vs. US Dollar: A 20-Year Comparison</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/economy/finance/stock%20market/2025/01/12/real-vs-usd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brazil’s Real vs. US Dollar: A 20-Year Comparison" /><published>2025-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/economy/finance/stock%20market/2025/01/12/real-vs-usd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/economy/finance/stock%20market/2025/01/12/real-vs-usd.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="brazils-real-vs-us-dollar-a-20-year-comparison">Brazil’s Real vs. US Dollar: A 20-Year Comparison</h1>

<p>Over the past 20 years, Brazil’s currency, the Real (BRL), has seen significant changes in value compared to the US Dollar (USD). This post examines the currency’s fluctuations and how Brazil’s stock market, represented by the Ibovespa Index, has performed over the same period.</p>

<h2 id="the-fluctuating-exchange-rate">The Fluctuating Exchange Rate</h2>

<p>The Real has experienced periods of both appreciation and depreciation, driven by factors like:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Global economic conditions</li>
  <li>Commodity prices</li>
  <li>Political and economic events within Brazil</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="key-milestones">Key Milestones</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>2005-2008:</strong> Appreciation due to high commodity demand.</li>
  <li><strong>2008-2010:</strong> Depreciation during the global financial crisis, followed by recovery.</li>
  <li><strong>2013-2016:</strong> Devaluation linked to political instability and falling commodity prices.</li>
  <li><strong>2020-2025:</strong> Stabilization post-COVID-19 economic recovery.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Graph 1:</strong> <em>Historical exchange rate of the Brazilian Real vs. the US Dollar over the last 20 years.</em>
<img src="/blog/img/posts/fred_bxus.png" alt="Historical exchange rate of the Brazilian Real vs. the US Dollar over the last 20 years." />
<img src="/blog/img/posts/fred_bxus.png" alt="Description of Image" width="600" height="400" /></p>

<h2 id="brazils-stock-market">Brazil’s Stock Market</h2>

<p>The Ibovespa Index reflects Brazil’s stock market performance and has shown resilience despite economic challenges.</p>

<h3 id="key-trends">Key Trends</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>2005-2007:</strong> Growth during the global commodities boom.</li>
  <li><strong>2008:</strong> Decline during the financial crisis.</li>
  <li><strong>2010-2014:</strong> Recovery with increased foreign investment.</li>
  <li><strong>2015-2018:</strong> Volatility due to political and economic turmoil.</li>
  <li><strong>2022-2025:</strong> Recent recovery amid economic reforms.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Graph 2:</strong> <em>Ibovespa Index performance from 2005 to 2025.</em></p>

<h2 id="comparing-real-and-ibovespa">Comparing Real and Ibovespa</h2>

<p>The relationship between the Real and the Ibovespa is complex. A weaker Real often benefits Brazilian exports, boosting stock performance. However, political and economic instability can affect both negatively.</p>

<p><strong>Graph 3:</strong> <em>Correlation between the Brazilian Real and the Ibovespa Index over 20 years.</em></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Both the Real and the Ibovespa have shown significant volatility, but they also reflect Brazil’s potential for economic growth and resilience. As Brazil continues to reform its economy, investors should remain vigilant and adapt to the opportunities and challenges in the market.</p>

<p>For additional data, visit the <a href="https://www.bcb.gov.br">Central Bank of Brazil</a> or the <a href="https://www.b3.com.br/en_us/">Ibovespa Index official page</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><category term="Economy" /><category term="Finance" /><category term="Stock Market" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brazil’s Real vs. US Dollar: A 20-Year Comparison]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dinosaurs are extinct today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dinosaurs are extinct today" /><published>2020-01-26T22:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T22:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs.html"><![CDATA[<p>Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</p>

<p>Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.</p>

<p>What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.</p>

<p>A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.</p>

<p>For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">The Final Frontier</h2>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<blockquote class="blockquote">The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.</blockquote>

<p>Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">Reaching for the Stars</h2>

<p>As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450" alt="Demo Image">
<span class="caption text-muted">To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.</span>

<p>Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.</p>

<p>As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.</p>

<p>Placeholder text by <a href="http://spaceipsum.com/">Space Ipsum</a>. Photographs by <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Start Bootstrap</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.]]></summary></entry></feed>